Evan Madden

(267) 314 - 7267 | evan.madden@gmail.com | Philadelphia, PA 19148 GitHub: /EvMad | Portfolio: https://evmad.github.io/portfolio-one/ LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/evan-madden-923474211/

Summary:

Web developer with a music industry background, a Web Development certificate from the University of Pennsylvania LPS bootcamp, and a BA in Music Technology. Currently completing a UX Design Certificate through Google Coursera. Technical strong points in custom CSS and CSS frameworks, vanilla JavaScript and JS server-side extensions, as well as both relational and non-relational databases. Soft skills developed over a decade of managing client experience and event production.

Technical Skills, Languages, and Applications:

MERN, GraphQL, React, Apollo Server, MongoDB, Git Bash, Node JS, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, jQuery, JavaScript, JS, ECMAScript6, ES6, Handlebars, HTML, Insomnia Core, Heroku, Cloudinary, Adobe XD, vanilla JavaScript, custom CSS, React Router, React in-line styling, XML, Markup, REST, RESTful, OOD, DOM, Scrum, Agile, SCSS, Sass, PWA, UI, UX, UX/UI, Usability, Accessibility, UI/UX

Recent Projects:

Community Canvas

Deployed: https://bit.lv/3CthrOx | Repo: https://bit.lv/3k2TZCE

Community Canvas is a full stack application developed for users to upload and view photos of street art, created with JavaScript, Sequelize, and MySQL. This role focused on learning to use Cloudinary as a digital assets management platform, as well as creating a mobile-first design.

BandFinder

Deployed: https://bit.ly/312sth0 | Repo: https://bit.ly/3BjKXa8

This group collaboration utilizes API's from Ticket Master and Deezer to provide data on upcoming live music by area, plus links to artist information. This role focused on using Bulma to create a streamlined user interface, as well as handling custom CSS, JavaScript, and HTML.

React Portfolio

Deployed: https://bit.ly/3sUnzPX Repo: https://bit.ly/3t038RE

React App created with React Router and XML in-line styling, and deployed via Heroku. This is a single page application using unique CSS for each component.

Relevant Employment:

Kung Fu Necktie March 2015-Present
Live Music Venue Philadelphia, PA

Engaged and retained new clients. Promoted from bartender to keyholder to manager.

- Tools: Google Calendar, PrismFM, Google Sheets, Social Media
- Role: Bar Manager, Show Runner, Concert Promoter
- Additional Responsibilities: ticket sales, targeted ad promotion, VIP ticket experiences

Riff Lifter Touring Talent Booking Agency

Feb 2011 - Feb 2018 Philadelphia, PA

Recruited artists, obtained work visas, and promoted concerts across the continent.

- Tools: Excel, Adobe Photoshop, Social Media
- Role: Booking Agent, Tour Manager
- Additional Responsibilities: data management, tour budgets, transportation logistics.

Education:

Google Coursera UX Design Certificate Program Oct 2021 - present

Web Development Certificate, BCS Coding Bootcamp University of Pennsylvania - August 2021

BA in Music, Recording Emphasis University of Maryland Baltimore County